{"question": "What do companies buy to create new technology?", "answer": "Companies buy resources needed to create new technology."}{"question": "What is the definition of technology?", "answer": "2."}{"question": "What is the definition of technology?", "answer": "Chapter 1 Technology and Development 1."}{"question": "What is the definition of technology?", "answer": "High: entirely or almost entirely automated and intelligent technology that manipulates ever finer matter and ever powerful forces."}{"question": "What is the definition of technology?", "answer": "Knowledge technology: What do people have to know 5 1."}{"question": "What is the definition of appropriate technology?", "answer": "2 Appropriate Technology Appropriate technology is an ideological movement (and its manifestations) originally articulated as intermediate technology by the economist Dr."}{"question": "What do engineers do?", "answer": "Engineers figure out how to make things."}{"question": "What is the meaning of technology?", "answer": "New inventions are almost always based on earlier accomplishments."}{"question": "What is the definition of technology?", "answer": "Intermediate: semiautomated partially intelligent technology that manipulates refined matter and medium level forces."}{"question": "What is the definition of technology?", "answer": "It involves turning natural items into useful products."}{"question": "What is the definition of technology?", "answer": "Low: labor-intensive technology that manipulates only coarse or gross matter and weaker forces Technology is the practical use of human knowledge to extend human abilities and to satisfy human needs and wants."}{"question": "What does technology mean?", "answer": "So technology means the \u201d scientific study of craft\u201d."}{"question": "How do they make things?", "answer": "Technologists make things by operating machines and assembling parts."}{"question": "What is the definition of technology?", "answer": "Intangible: consultancy, problem-solving, and training methods."}{"question": "What does technology mean?", "answer": "Craft in this case, means any method or invention that allow humans to control or adapt to their environment."}{"question": "What do scientists try to explain?", "answer": "Scientists try to explain how things happen."}{"question": "Why did technology develop?", "answer": "Technology developed because people had ideas they turned into useful devices."}{"question": "What is the meaning of technology?", "answer": "1 Introduction to Technology The word technology made from Greek words techne which means \u201dcraft\u201d and -logy means \u201d scientific study of\u201d."}{"question": "What are the three aspects of technology?", "answer": "Three aspects of technology 1."}{"question": "What is the most important aspect of technology?", "answer": "Operations Technology: What task are being performed 2."}{"question": "How does technology advance?", "answer": "Technology advances by adapting, so each new product is an improvement over an existing one."}{"question": "What are the three areas of science, technology, and engineering?", "answer": "The areas of science, technology, and engineering are related but different."}{"question": "What are the resources of technology?", "answer": "Resources of technology include people, information, tools and machines, capital, time,materials, and energy."}{"question": "What is the definition of technology?", "answer": "4."}{"question": "What is the definition of technology?", "answer": "Tangible: blueprints, models, operating manuals, prototypes."}{"question": "Who wrote Small is Beautiful?", "answer": "Ernst Friedrich \u201dFritz\u201d Schumacher in his influential work, Small is Beautiful."}{"question": "What is the definition of technology?", "answer": "5."}{"question": "What are the main categories of technology?", "answer": "Technology is generally divided into five categories 1."}{"question": "What is the definition of technology?", "answer": "-Scientific application of knowledge -Systematic application of organized knowledge and tangibles(tools and material) The purposeful application of information in the design, production, and utilization of goods and services, and in the organization of human activities."}{"question": "What is the meaning of technology?", "answer": "Both Schumacher and many modern-day proponents of appropriate technology also emphasize the technology as people-centered."}{"question": "What is the definition of technology?", "answer": "3."}{"question": "What are the three aspects of technology?", "answer": "Material technology: What material and supplies are used 3."}{"question": "What is the definition of technology?", "answer": "Though the nuances of appropriate technology vary between fields and applications, it is generally recognized as encompassing technological choice and application that is small-scale, decentralized, labor-intensive, energy-efficient, environmentally sound, and locally controlled."}{"question": "What are the main characteristics of technology?", "answer": "They hire people with the knowledge and skill to make products."}{"question": "What is the most common discussion of appropriate technology?", "answer": "Appropriate technology is most commonly discussed in its relationship to economic development and as an alternative to transfers of capital-intensive technology from industrialized nations to developing countries."}{"question": "Who is the founder of the appropriate technology movement?", "answer": "Dr."}{"question": "What is the name of the new model of enabling innovation for sustainable development?", "answer": "OSAT has been proposed as a new model of enabling innovation for sustainable development."}{"question": "Who is credited with the appropriate technology movement?", "answer": "Ernst Friedrich \u201dFritz\u201d Schumacher is credited as the founder of the appropriate technology movement."}{"question": "What is the name of the appropriate technology movement?", "answer": "Today appropriate technology is often developed using open source principles, which have led to open-source appropriate technology (OSAT) and thus many of the plans of the technology can be freely found on the Internet."}{"question": "What is the main focus of the appropriate technology movement?", "answer": "In developed countries, the appropriate technology movement grew out of the energy crisis of the 1970s and focuses mainly on environmental and sustainability issues."}{"question": "What is the meaning of appropriate technology?", "answer": "Schumacher described the concept of appropriate technology to a mass audience in his influential work, Small is Beautiful: Economics as if People Mattered."}{"question": "Where can you find appropriate technology?", "answer": "However, appropriate technology movements can be found in both developing and developed countries."}{"question": "What was the name of the movement?", "answer": "Schumacher first articulated the idea of \u201dintermediate technology,\u201d now known as appropriate technology, in a 1962 report to the Indian Planning Commission in which he described India as long in labor and short in capital, calling for an \u201dintermediate industrial technology\u201d that harnessed India\u2019s labor surplus."}{"question": "What was Schumacher\u2019s first known critique of the effects of Western economics on developing countries?", "answer": "In 1955, following a stint as an economic advisor to the government of Burma, he published the short paper \u201dEconomics in a Buddhist Country,\u201d his first known critique of the effects of Western economics on developing countries."}{"question": "Who rejected Schumacher\u2019s ideas?", "answer": "Initially, Schumacher\u2019s ideas were rejected by both the Indian government and leading development economists."}{"question": "Who was Schumacher credited with?", "answer": "In addition to Buddhism, Schumacher also credited his ideas to Gandhi."}{"question": "How long had Schumacher been developing the idea of appropriate technology?", "answer": "Schumacher had been developing the idea of intermediate technology for several years prior to the Planning Commission report."}{"question": "What is the meaning of appropriate technology?", "answer": "Appropriate technology has been used to address issues in a wide range of fields."}{"question": "What are some examples of appropriate technology?", "answer": "Well-known examples of appropriate technology applications include: bike- and hand-powered water pumps (and other self-powered equipment), the universal nut sheller, self-contained solar-powered light bulbs and street lights, and passive solar building designs."}{"question": "How many people formed the Intermediate Technology Development Group in May 1965?", "answer": "Spurred to action over concern the idea of intermediate technology would languish, Schumacher, George McRobie, Mansur Hoda and Julia Porter brought together a group of approximately 20 people to form the Intermediate Technology Development Group (ITDG) in May 1965."}{"question": "What are the characteristics of appropriate technology?", "answer": "organizational simplicity 4."}{"question": "What are the characteristics of appropriate technology?", "answer": "make technology understandable to the people who are using it and thus suggest ideas that could be used in further innovations 10."}{"question": "What are the characteristics of appropriate technology?", "answer": "According to Jequier and Gerard (1993), \u201dAppropriate Technology (AT)\u201d is now recognized as the generic term for a wide range of technologies characterized by following features: 1."}{"question": "What are the characteristics of appropriate technology?", "answer": "involve decentralized renewable energy sources, such as wind power, solar energy, water power, mechanic gas, animal power and pedal power (such as in that highly efficient machine, the bicycle) 9."}{"question": "What are some characteristics of appropriate technologies?", "answer": "Some characteristics of appropriate technologies are listed below."}{"question": "What are the characteristics of appropriate technology?", "answer": "use local materials whenever possible 3."}{"question": "What is the definition of appropriate technology?", "answer": "TECHNOLOGY TRANSFER 7 6."}{"question": "What are the characteristics of appropriate technology?", "answer": "low capital investment per unit of output 3."}{"question": "What is the definition of appropriate technology?", "answer": "suppose that people can and will work together to collectively bring improvements to their communities, recognizing that in most of the world important decisions are made by groups rather than by individuals 8."}{"question": "What are the characteristics of appropriate technology?", "answer": "Using Renewable Energy Sources 1."}{"question": "What is the definition of appropriate technology?", "answer": "sparing use of natural resources 6."}{"question": "What are the characteristics of appropriate technology?", "answer": "high adaptability to a particular social cultural environment 5."}{"question": "What is the definition of appropriate technology?", "answer": "3 Technology Transfer Technology transfer, also called transfer of technology (TOT), is the process of transferring skills, knowledge, technologies, methods of manufacturing, samples of manufacturing and facilities among governments or universities and other institutions to ensure that scientific and technological developments are accessible to a wider range of users who can then further develop and exploit the technology into new products, processes, applications, materials or services."}{"question": "How can a small metal working shop be produced?", "answer": "can be produced out of a small metal working shop, if not in a village itself 7."}{"question": "What are the characteristics of appropriate technology?", "answer": "Environmentally friendly 7."}{"question": "Who is responsible for the production of the technology?", "answer": "Manufactured and Operated by local labor and expertise 6."}{"question": "What are the characteristics of appropriate technology?", "answer": "Characteristics Importance of Appropriate Technology Appropriate technology was meant to address four problems: extreme poverty, starvation, unemployment and urban migration."}{"question": "What are the characteristics of appropriate technology?", "answer": "low investment cost per work place 2."}{"question": "What is the definition of appropriate technology?", "answer": "can be understood, controlled and maintained by villagers wherever possible, without high level of Western style education 1."}{"question": "What are the characteristics of appropriate technologies?", "answer": "are flexible so that they can continue to be used or adapted to fit changing circumstances 11."}{"question": "What are the characteristics of appropriate technology?", "answer": "Affordable to those people being considered 4."}{"question": "What are the characteristics of appropriate technology?", "answer": "Meets the actual need of people 3."}{"question": "What is the importance of appropriate technology?", "answer": "Optimization of local Resources 5."}{"question": "What are the characteristics of appropriate technologies?", "answer": "According to Darrow and Rick (1978), appropriate technologies: 1."}{"question": "What are the characteristics of appropriate technology?", "answer": "do not involve patents, royalties, consultant fees, import duties, shopping changes; practical plans can be obtained free of cost and no further payment is involved."}{"question": "What are the characteristics of appropriate technologies?", "answer": "are low in capital costs 2."}{"question": "What is the definition of appropriate technology?", "answer": "3."}{"question": "What are the characteristics of appropriate technology?", "answer": "create jobs, employing local skills and labor 4."}{"question": "What are the characteristics of appropriate technology?", "answer": "are small enough in scale to be affordable by a small group of farmers 5."}{"question": "What are the characteristics of appropriate technology?", "answer": "low cost of final product or high potential for employment."}{"question": "What are the characteristics of appropriate technology?", "answer": "Suited to the societies being considered 2."}{"question": "What are the characteristics of appropriate technology?", "answer": "1."}{"question": "What is the definition of technology transfer?", "answer": "At present transfer of technology (TOT) is primarily horizontal."}{"question": "What is the importance of technology transfer?", "answer": "Universities protect their investments in research by patenting new technologies, which gives them an opportunity to reach the stream of commerce."}{"question": "What is the importance of technology transfer?", "answer": "In addition, technology transfer ensures that the interests and rights of the university in the intellectual property are protected."}{"question": "What is the importance of technology transfer?", "answer": "The university\u2019s investments in the technology help stimulate local economic development."}{"question": "What is the importance of technology transfer?", "answer": "Importance of Technology Transfer Technology transfer helps develop early stage intellectual property into tools for direct use by the research community, or into bases for new platforms, products, or services to be made into products for public use."}{"question": "What are the benefits of technology transfer?", "answer": "These collaborations may result in licensing or sponsored research opportunities that benefit both partners."}{"question": "What is the role of the TTO?", "answer": "Many companies, universities and governmental organizations now have an Office of Technology Transfer(TTO) dedicated to identifying research which has potential commercial interest and strategies for how to exploit it."}{"question": "Who is the ultimate beneficiary of technology transfer?", "answer": "The ultimate beneficiary of technology transfer is the public, who benefits from both the products that reach the market and the jobs resulting from the development, manufacturing, and sale of products."}{"question": "What is the importance of technology transfer?", "answer": "Technology transfer requires a proactive approach that combines engaging researchers, promoting the technology, and encouraging potential industrial partners to use the technology."}{"question": "What is the role of the university in the transfer of technology?", "answer": "The university is able to retain the intellectual property rights of the technology and issue a license for the conditional use of the technology."}{"question": "What is the meaning of technology transfer?", "answer": "1: Process of technology transfer It is closely related to (and may arguably be considered a subset of) knowledge transfer."}{"question": "What is the importance of technology transfer?", "answer": "Industry partners can also reduce the costs incurred during their research and development stage by licensing technology from a university."}{"question": "What are the main characteristics of the transfer process?", "answer": "The dynamics of the technology transfer process has attracted attention in its own right, and there are several dedicated societies and journals."}{"question": "What is the importance of technology transfer?", "answer": "Successful collaborations are formed between researchers across different universities or industries in order to advance the knowledge in a particular field or to further develop a technology."}{"question": "What is the purpose of the transfer of technology?", "answer": "The research result may be of scientific and commercial interest."}{"question": "What is the definition of technology transfer?", "answer": "Horizontal transfer is the movement of technologies from one area to another."}{"question": "What is the main benefit of technology transfer?", "answer": "Another benefit for the university involves using the licensing revenue to support further research and education at the institution."}{"question": "What is the importance of technology transfer?", "answer": "Successful transfer and development of the technology helps promote the research institution and its commercial partners."}{"question": "What is the importance of technology transfer?", "answer": "3."}{"question": "What is the meaning of technology transfer?", "answer": "Figure 1."}{"question": "What are the types of people involved in the technology transfer process?", "answer": "As a result of the potential complexity of the technology transfer process, technology transfer organizations are often multidisciplinary, including economists, engineers, lawyers, marketers and scientists."}{"question": "What is the importance of technology transfer?", "answer": "The university obtains recognition and increases its reputation for their research and innovation potential."}{"question": "What is the definition of vertical transfer?", "answer": "Vertical transfer occurs when technologies are moved from applied research centers to research and development departments."}{"question": "What is the impact of technology on society?", "answer": "2."}{"question": "What is the impact of technology on society?", "answer": "So, with the huge impact that technology has on society and public opinion in particular, it is crucial to be cautious in the use of information about any political figure, or you risk making a positive advertisement into a negative advertisement with just one click."}{"question": "What is the impact of technology on society?", "answer": "Economic System In the modern world, superior technologies, resources, geography, and history give rise to robust economies; and in a well-functioning, robust economy, economic excess naturally flows into greater use of technology."}{"question": "What is the impact of technology on society?", "answer": "The progress of the innovation of technology is continuing to improve the education sector for coming generations."}{"question": "What is the meaning of technology?", "answer": "4 Impact of Technology on Society Technology and society or technology and culture refers to cyclical co-dependence, co-influence, coproduction of technology and society upon the other."}{"question": "What is the impact of technology on society?", "answer": "The article analyzed is good in arranging technological tools into separate groups that work as effective means of communication between a political figure and the target audience."}{"question": "What is the difference between the two?", "answer": "However, to every coin there is a flip side."}{"question": "What is the impact of technology on society?", "answer": "Teachers are using digital technology as an essential tool to help in guiding lessons and student\u2019s communication."}{"question": "What is the impact of technology on society?", "answer": "So, not just the good, but also a bad reputation can be formed in a blink of an eye using modern technology."}{"question": "What is the impact of technology on society?", "answer": "It provides children, who have difficulties in learning the traditional way, with educational games that would help them in the process of learning."}{"question": "How many people are involved in the development of technology?", "answer": "However, while in the beginning, technological investment involved little more than the time, efforts, and skills of one or a few men, today, such investment may involve the collective labor and skills of many millions."}{"question": "What is the impact of technology on society?", "answer": "Education Modern technologies have made instructive information for classrooms and home assignments easier and simpler."}{"question": "How long have computers been in the education frame?", "answer": "In fact, computers have been in the education frame globally for a long period of time."}{"question": "What is the impact of technology on society?", "answer": "When an innovation achieves a certain point after it is been presented and promoted, this technology becomes part of the society."}{"question": "What is the meaning of the term?", "answer": "Students today are called \u2019screenagers\u2019, \u2019digital natives\u2019 or \u2019digital kids\u2019 because they were born in a complicated digital world based on technology."}{"question": "What is the impact of technology on society?", "answer": "Technology has become a huge part of every day societies life."}{"question": "What is the impact of technology on society?", "answer": "Moreover, because technology is such an inseparable part of human society, especially in its economic aspects, funding sources for (new) technological endeavors are virtually illimitable."}{"question": "What is the impact of technology on society?", "answer": "4."}{"question": "What is the impact of technology on society?", "answer": "Politics It is clear that gaining political publicity through the use of technology has become easier, especially since technological devices are so accessible and widespread at the same time."}{"question": "What are the advantages of online courses?", "answer": "Alternatively from attending classes, online courses are offered to college students in advantage."}{"question": "What is the impact of technology on society?", "answer": "Students are associating with others more globally and learning more things in varied ways than at any time in the past."}{"question": "How does the impact of technology on society differ from the other aspects of society?", "answer": "With the use of Internet, any political figure can become recognizable within just a few minutes."}{"question": "What is the impact of technology on society?", "answer": "Digital technology has entered each process and activity made by the social system."}{"question": "What is the impact of technology on society?", "answer": "In only a few hours public opinion on a particular political figure is already formed within one of the social groups of voters."}{"question": "What is the impact of technology on society?", "answer": "It often happens that the bad \u201dgossip\u201d actually spreads much faster."}{"question": "What is the impact of technology on society?", "answer": "IMPACT OF TECHNOLOGY ON SOCIETY 9 3."}{"question": "What is the impact of technology on society?", "answer": "The impact of technologies on society can broadly studies by dividing aspects of societies as 1."}{"question": "What is the impact of technology on society?", "answer": "When societies knows more about the development in a technology, they become able to advantage from it."}{"question": "What is the impact of technology on society?", "answer": "1."}{"question": "What is the best way to spread information?", "answer": "However, those who believe voluntary euthanasia is a good option are forbidden to use electronic means to distribute information."}{"question": "What are the main reasons why people can propagate their views?", "answer": "Others can propagate alternative views, but mainstream religions are well funded and run by zealots."}{"question": "What are the effects of technology on the environment?", "answer": "The more subtle effects include debates over long-term effect(e."}{"question": "What is the impact on religion?", "answer": "In summary impact on religion can be viewed as (a) Its more accessible (b) Distance doesnt matter as much (c) Reputations are shifting (d) Stats become important (e) Laity gets involved (f) Theres increased focus on strategy 5."}{"question": "What are the main effects of technology on the environment?", "answer": ", global warming, deforestation, natural habitat destruction, coastal wetland loss."}{"question": "What is the difference between the two?", "answer": "Different social and political systems establish different balances between the value they place on additional goods versus the disvalues of waste products and pollution."}{"question": "What are some technologies designed first for?", "answer": "Some technologies are designed specifically with the environment in mind, but most are designed first for economic or ergonomic effects."}{"question": "What is the effect of technology on the environment?", "answer": "It seems that religious organisations still obtain favoured treatment on early morning TV, more so than other groups in society."}{"question": "What is the value of a clean environment and more efficient productive processes?", "answer": "Historically, the value of a clean environment and more efficient productive processes has been the result of an increase in the wealth of society, because once people are able to provide for their basic needs, they are able to focus on less-tangible goods such as clean air and water."}{"question": "What are the effects of technology on the environment?", "answer": "The more obvious effects include the depletion of non-renewable natural resources (such as petroleum, coal, ores), and the added pollution of air, water, and land."}{"question": "What is the most common type of waste produced by modern technology?", "answer": "Most modern technological processes produce unwanted by products in addition to the desired products, which is known as industrial waste and pollution."}{"question": "What are the main reasons why people use the internet to spread their beliefs?", "answer": "There are many websites that propagate untruths about science and religion, seek money for \u2019truths\u2019 about imaginary beings, advocate discrimination or that gods can kill or do inappropriate things."}{"question": "What is the impact of technology on the environment?", "answer": "g."}{"question": "What is the impact of technology on the environment?", "answer": "4."}{"question": "What does technology provide?", "answer": "Environment Technology provides an understanding, and an appreciation for the world around us."}{"question": "How can religions spread their views?", "answer": "Religions can propagate their views more widely using global technologies such as over the internet."}{"question": "What is the impact of technology on the environment?", "answer": "Freedom of speech is important, but well-funded religions can propagate untruths and discriminatory values faster than less well-funded organisations."}{"question": "What are the main effects of technology on the environment?", "answer": "While most material waste is re-used in the industrial process, many forms are released into the environment, with negative environmental side effects, such as pollution and lack of sustainability."}{"question": "What is the danger of indoctrination of children?", "answer": "There is a danger that the indoctrination of children, discrimination and the imposition of religious values on others could worsen before it improves."}{"question": "What can be used to propagate religion?", "answer": "Religion Religions can use electronic technologies to propagate their beliefs."}{"question": "What are the effects of technology on the environment?", "answer": "The effects of technology on the environment are both obvious and subtle."}{"question": "what is the waste of a wave of technology?", "answer": "Each wave of technology creates a set of waste previously unknown by humans: toxic waste, radioactive waste, electronic waste."}